撕裂的末日
21世紀初期
DUPONT: In the first years of the 21 st century...
第三次世界大戰爆發
...a third World War broke out.
我們那些活下來的人深知...
Those of us who survived knew
再歷經第四次...
mankind could never survive...
人類便不可能再存活下去
a fourth...
我們易變的天性
that our own volatile natures
無法再冒這種險了
could simply no longer be risked.
所以我們組織了一支法律新兵
So we have created a new arm of the law...
[Gun cocks]
...耶和華教士
...the Grammaton Cleric,
唯一任務便是找出並消弭...
whose sole task it is to seek out and eradicate
人對人殘暴的真正來源
the true source of man's inhumanity to man.
他要有能力...
His ability...
察覺的出來
to feel.
[Thud]
警察!
Police!
[Tires screech]
[Men shouting indistinctly]
[Guns cocking]
你們懂得怎麼辦
You know what to do.
[Guns cocking]
[Indistinct shouting]
[Glass shattering]
趴下!
Get down!
[Gunfire and shouting fade]
[Gunfire in distance]
目前不清楚有多少人
MAN: We have an unknown number
在大樓東南方作頑劣抵抗
barricaded in the southeast end of the compound.
收到,耶和華隊正趕過去
MAN #2: Read that. Tetragrammaton team en route.
教士,裡頭關了燈,也許不只12個人
Cleric, lights out. Maybe more than a dozen inside.
門撞破後,就把燈泡打破
When the door's down, blow the bulbs.
遵命,長官
Yes, sir.
[Guns cocking]
行動
Go.
[Suspenseful clock-like rhythm]
[Thud, gunfire]
[Gunfire stops]
他人呢?
MAN: Where is he?
閉嘴
MAN #2: Shut up.
有誰抓到他? 打中他了嗎?
Anybody get him? Did anybody hit him?
閉嘴!
Shut up!
聽好
Listen.
[Gunfire, men screaming]
[Gunfire stops, casings rattle]
[Clicking]
[Footsteps]
[Casings jingling]
[Squealing]
[Clicking]
這就是了
This is it.
哪裡?
Where?
那裡
There.
[Wood splintering]
[Clicks, whines]
[Beeps]
是真品
It's real.
燒掉
Burn it.
你為何不把它留著
Why didn't you just leave it
給證物組採集登記?
for the evidentiary team to collect and log?
他們有時會弄丟
They miss things sometimes.
[Exhales deeply]
我想還是自己拿...
And I thought I'd take it down myself...
比較保險
get it done properly.
培斯頓,這還要多久才會結束?
How long, Preston, till all this is gone?
直到我們燒光每一點一滴嗎?
Till we've burned every last bit of it?
資源緊迫
Resources are tight.
我們終究會得到的
We'll get it all eventually.
利比亞...
DUPONT: Libria...
恭喜你
I congratulate you.
到最後...
At last...
和平統治人心
peace reigns in the heart of man.
到最後,戰爭只不過是個名詞
At last, war is but a word
它所代表意義逐漸為人所淡忘
whose meaning fades from our understanding.
到最後...
At last...
萬眾...結為...一體
we... are... whole.
[Motors humming]
利比亞人...人心潛藏著一種疾病
Librians... there is a disease in the heart of man.
它的癥狀是仇恨
Its symptom is hate.
它的癥狀...是生氣
Its symptom... is anger.
它的癥狀是憤怒
Its symptom is rage.
它的癥狀...是戰爭
Its symptom... is war.
這種病...便是人類情感
The disease... is human emotion.
但,利比亞...我在此向你們道賀
But, Libria... I congratulate you.
因為此種病可以醫治
For there is a cure for this disease.
犧牲人類情感的波濤起伏
At the cost of the dizzying highs of human emotion,
我們已經徹底抑制住病情
we have suppressed its abysmal lows.
身處社會一份子的你們享有這種治療品
And you as a society have embraced this cure.
[Clicking]
波西安
Prozium.
[Whirs]
如今我們和平共處
Now we are at peace with ourselves,
人類團結一心
and humankind is one.
戰爭消失了
War is gone.
仇恨成了回憶
Hate, a memory.
我們現在成了自己的良知
We are our own conscience now.
正是這種良知引導我們去評定EC-10級
And it is this conscience that guides us to rate EC-10
在情感方面
for emotional content
凡是那些可能再次誘發我們情感的事物
all those things that might tempt us to feel again...
一律銷毀
and destroy them.
利比亞人,你們已經勝利了
Librians, you have won.
難能可貴的是憑著你們自己的本性...
Against all odds and your own natures...
你們已經活了下來
you have survived.
[Beeping]
[Beep]
每次從尼瑟斯到這城裡來
Every time we come from the Nethers to the city,
就提醒我們一舉一動的原因
it reminds why we do what we do.
是嗎?
It does?
你說什麼?
I beg your pardon.
[Clicks, whirs]
沒錯
It does.
[Whirs]
[Clicks, whirs]
下列項目已經被評定為EC-10級...
WOMAN: The following items have been rated EC-10...
依法充公...
condemned...
七件平面畫刊雜誌
seven works of two-dimensional illustrated material,
七張音樂光碟
seven discs of musical content,
20種互動戰略電腦程式
20 interactive strategy computer programs.
七件平面...
MAN: Seven works of two-dimensional...
[Voice fades]
[Bell chiming]
謝謝你來,教士
DUPONT: Thank you for coming, Cleric.
猜想你知道我是誰
I assume you know who I am.
當然明白,長官
Yes, sir. Of course.
你是副主席杜彭
You are Vice-Council Dupont
耶和華組織第三屆議院院長...
of the Third Conciliarly of the Tetragrammaton...
神父的發言人
Father's voice.
坦白說, 教士
Quite frankly, Cleric,
有人告訴我你真是大材小用
I am told that you are very nearly a prodigal student,
只要有人觸發情感,你幾乎能立即察覺
knowing almost instantly if someone is feeling.
我的紀錄優良,長官
I have a good record, sir.
為何那樣,你憑想像的嗎,教士?
Why, do you imagine, that is, Cleric?
我不確定,副主席
I'm not sure, Vice-Council.
總之...
Somehow...
就某種程度而言,我能夠...
I'm able, on some level,
察覺罪犯的想法
to sense how an offender thinks,
設身處地去想
to... put myself in their position.
如果你們處於同等地位
If you had ceased your interval,
如果你身為感情罪犯...
if you were a sense offender...
我想你說的沒錯,長官
I suppose you could say that, sir.
你有家室嗎,教士?
You're a family man, Cleric?
有的,長官...一兒一女
Yes, sir... a boy and a girl.
我兒在修道院中學習
The boy's in the monastery himself,
以成為教士為目標
on path to becoming a Cleric.
很好
Good.
孩子母親呢?
And the mother?
我的配偶在四年前因情感罪
My spouse was arrested and incinerated
遭逮捕並火化了,長官
for sense offense four years ago, sir.
你執行的?
By yourself?
不是,長官...另有其人
No, sir... by another.
你對那件事作何感想?
How did you feel about that?
對不起
I'm sorry.
我不太...完全理解你的意思,長官
I don't... fully understand, sir.
你有何感受?
How did you feel?
一點感覺也沒有
I didn't feel anything.
真的?
Really?
你怎麼竟然會疏忽了呢?
How is it that you came to miss it?
我...
I...
我問過自己同樣的問題,長官
I've asked myself that same question, sir.
我不知道
I don't know.
不容許任何小小過失,教士
A nearly unforgivable lapse, Cleric.
我相信你今後會更加提防小心
I trust you'll be more vigilant in the future.
是的,長官
Yes, sir.
每次從尼瑟斯到這城裡來
PRESTON: Every time we come from the Nethers to the city,
就提醒我們一舉一動的原因
it reminds why we do what we do.
是嗎?
PARTRIDGE: It does?
[Tape rewinding]
每次從尼瑟斯到這城裡來
Every time we come from the Nethers to the city,
就提醒我們一舉一動的原因
it reminds why we do what we do.
是嗎?
It does?
[Click, tape rewinds]
沒錯
It does.
A.N.R.編號136890的原告證物
Prosecutorial evidence for A.N.R. 136890.
我需要它
I need it.
就今天傍晚的事
It was late this afternoon.
可能紀錄裡尚未顯示
May not have showed up in the records yet.
[Doors whir, click]
非常抱歉,教士
I'm very sorry, Cleric.
還沒有紀錄上去
Nothing has been logged
記載事項裡並未有審訊中的東西
and nothing is pending under that entry.
是經由艾洛·帕崔吉教士
It was an item of evidence brought in personally
親自攜帶過來的一件證物
by Grammaton Errol Partridge.
再查一遍
Check again.
長官,帕崔吉教士好幾個星期 沒繳交任何物品了
Sir, Cleric Partridge has not entered anything in for weeks.
你弄錯了,是某種書籍之類的
You're mistaken. It was a book of some kind.
教士...
Cleric...
[Stand scrapes]
...空空如也
...there's nothing.
謝謝
Thank you.
他一直通過,進入尼瑟斯大樓的大門
He's been passing through the gate into the Nether
近兩星期以來,每晚如此
every night for the last two weeks.
我們假設是執行任務
We assumed it was enforcement-related.
[Motor whirs]
[Wind blowing]
[Footsteps]
你總是知道
You always knew.
"而我,孑然一身...
"But I, being poor...
徒留我的夢想"
have only my dreams."
"在你腳下展開夢想之翼"
"I have spread my dreams under your feet.
"輕輕地踩著步伐...
"Tread softly...
因為你踩在我的夢想之翼上"
because you tread on my dreams."
相信你也作過夢,培斯頓
I assume you dream, Preston.
我會盡量叫他們放你一馬
I'll do what I can to see they go easy on you.
我倆皆知...不可能饒過我的
We both know... they never go easy.
那麼我很抱歉了
Then I'm sorry.
不,你才不會抱歉
No, you're not.
你甚至不懂抱歉的涵義
You don't even know the meaning.
只是一個...退化的字眼
It's just a... vestigial word
對於一種你未曾感受過的情感
for a feeling you've never felt.
你不明白嗎,培斯頓?
Don't you see, Preston?
它早已消失無蹤
It's gone.
造就我們今日的一切...已不復存在
Everything that makes us what we are... traded away.
沒有戰爭
There's no war.
沒有謀殺
No murder.
那你認為我們做的事是什麼呢?
What is it you think we do?
不
No.
你一直和我在一起
You've been with me.
你見識過嫉妒、憤怒的下場
You've seen how it can be... the jealousy, the rage.
慘痛的代價
A heavy cost.
我很樂意付出
I'd pay it gladly.
[Gun cocks]
別動
Don't.
[Clicks]
[Gun cocks]
[Casing rattles]
[Wind blowing]
[Footsteps]
你和你的前任搭很要好?
You and your partner were close?
希望你會高興我被指派來
I hope you're as pleased to be assigned me
替補這個缺
as I am the placement.
聽說這是個飛黃騰達的良機
I was told this would be a career-making advancement.
我跟你一樣,教士...具有第六感
I'm like you, Cleric... intuitive.
偶爾連別人自己尚未察覺之前
Sometimes I know when a person's feeling
我就察覺到他有情感了
before they know it themselves.
教士...
Cleric...
我只希望有一天能像你那樣...
I can only hope one day to be as...
大公無私
uncompromising as you.
晚安
Good night.
20世紀末
The later 20th century
偶然同時崛起了
saw the fortuitous and simultaneous rise
多功能政治和心理科學
of two synergistic political and psychological sciences.
首先制定了仇恨罪行的革命性方針
The first, the revolutionary precept of the hate crime.
[Click]
約翰?
John?
什麼事?
Yes?
我今天看到羅比·泰勒在哭
I saw Robbie Taylor crying today.
他並不知道,不過我看見了
He didn't know, but I saw.
你認為我該舉發他嗎?
Do you think I should report him?
當然
Unquestionably.
[Click]
一項無可避免的事實...
...a single inescapable fact...
人類因遠大理想而結合
that mankind united with infinitely greater purpose
而追求戰爭...
in pursuit of war...
卻遠超過追求和平
than he ever did in pursuit of peace.
"而我,孑然一身...
PARTRIDGE: "But I, being poor...
徒留我的夢想"
have only my dreams."
"在你腳下展開夢想之翼"
I have spread my dreams under your feet."
"輕輕地踩著步伐...
"Tread softly...
因為你踩在我的夢想之翼上"
because you tread on my dreams."
別動! 別動!
Don't move! Don't move!
順從! 順從!
Comply! Comply!
住手! 站住別動! 趴下! 趴下!
- Stop! Stop where you are! - Get down! Get down!
- [Crackling] - [Grunts]
[Grunts]
別開槍,這是合法進入
Don't shoot. This is a lawful entry.
我們有逮捕你妻子的逮捕狀
We have a warrant for your wife's arrest.
她被指控觸犯情感罪
She's charged with sense offense.
嘿!
- [Gasps] - Hey!
抓住她! 馬上抓走
Get her! Get her off him now!
記得我
Remember me.
利比亞...
- DUPONT: Libria... - [Thunder rumbling]
醒來吧
Awake.
醒來面對另一天再次的勝利
Awaken to triumph again in the face of yet another day,
邁向統一境界
another step in our unified march
屹立不搖...
- into the unwavering purpose... - [Thunder rumbles]
[Voice fades]
...一起向前邁進
...move ahead together
乃我們共同體必然的趨勢
into the certainty of our collective destiny.
[Faucet squeaks]
[Glass shatters]
你在做什麼?
ROBBIE: What are you doing?
我說,你在做什麼?
I said, what are you doing?
我不小心掉了我的...
I accidently dropped my...
早針
morning interval.
我刷牙前先拿了出來
I took it out before I brushed my teeth.
我從未在刷牙前拿出來
I never take it out before I brush my teeth.
那你要去平衡處登記遺失
Then you'll go by Equilibrium, log the loss,
再補拿一個
and get a replacement.
沒錯
Yes.
當然
Of course.
你的新搭檔來過電話
Your new partner called.
他說十點鐘來載你到A.N.R.
He says he'll pick you up at 10:00 for the A.N.R.
希望你別介意
I hope you don't mind.
我擅自告訴他
I took the liberty of telling him
你會到平衡處換取注射藥劑
you would be at Equilibrium, replacing your dose.
不,當然不介意
No, of course not.
你做的很正確
That was the right thing to do.
[Rattling]
別那樣
Stop that.
由於恐怖份子活動
MAN AND WOMAN ALTERNATING: Due to terrorist activity,
本站暫時關閉
this site is temporarily closed.
請前往平衡中心8A區
Proceed to the Equilibrium Center in Sector 8A.
由於恐怖份子活動
Due to terrorist activity,
本站暫時關閉
this site is temporarily closed.
MAN: This site is temporarily closed.
請前往平衡中心8A區
Proceed to the Equilibrium Center in Sector 8A.
太過準時了,教士
More than punctual, Cleric.
上車吧
Hop in.
[Tires screech]
你打算如何?
How were the lines?
想不到你竟能拿到你的注射劑
I'm surprised you were able to get your interval
並如此迅速地出來
and get out so quickly.
不,他們...早上時候還沒事
No, they're... they're fine today.
[Engine idling]
也許我晚一點經過 也順便調整一下我的注射劑
Maybe I'll drop by later, get my interval adjusted.
[Gun cocks]
你想去抓反抗份子?
You expecting Resistance?
你遲早會發現,教士
That's something you'll find about me, Cleric.
我是個謹慎的人,天生機警
I'm a wary person, cautious by nature.
總是作最壞的打算
Always expecting the worst.
[Thud, metal rattles]
你們不能這樣,你們不能這樣!
You can't do this. You cannot do this.
耶和華 我們無所不能
Tetragrammaton. There's nothing we can't do.
[Grunts]
你多久沒服藥了?
How long have you been off the dose?
看看你
Look at you.
[Gasps]
看看你!
Look at you!
[Breathing heavily]
看看你
Look at you.
鏡架是非法的,砸了它
The mirror's frame is illegal. Destroy it.
情況穩住了,我們正要進入搜查
MAN: We have suppression. We're making entry.
標準佈署
MAN #2: Standard deployment.
搜集非法物品等罪狀
Collecting catalog. Illegal articles.
[Glass shatters]
你要燒掉是嗎?
You're gonna burn it, aren't you?
[Bell jingles]
終究得燒掉
Eventually.
無論如何,你不能私自堆積這全部物品
However, you couldn't have accumulated all this by yourself.
全部會被分類檢查
It'll all be sorted and examined.
我們會找出你的同黨
We'll discover who your confederates are.
小心槍!
Gun!
[Breathing heavily]
我們需要她
We need her.
你叫什麼名字?
What's your name?
瑪麗·歐布萊恩
O'Brien, Mary.
嗯,瑪麗...
Well, Mary...
你可以繼續等
you can either wait
去對法院那些專家說...
and tell the technicians at the Palace of Justice...
或者現在就告訴我
or you can tell me now.
你的朋友有誰?
Who are your friends?
我懷疑你是否真的明白...
I'm wondering if you have any idea at all
"朋友"這個字的意義
what that word means... "friend."
你什麼感覺也沒有嗎?
There's nothing you don't feel?
罪惡感呢?
How about guilt?
我請教你一件事
Let me ask you something.
[Glass clatters]
你為何活著?
Why are you alive?
我活著...
I'm alive...
我生存...
I live...
...是為了捍衛此偉大社會的延續
...to safeguard the continuity of this great society.
為利比亞效忠
To serve Libria.
只是種生命循環
It's circular.
你是為了延續你的生存而生存
You exist to continue your existence.
重點何在?
What's the point?
那你生存重點又何在?
What's the point of your existence?
去感覺
To feel.
因為你沒試過,所以你永遠不懂
'Cause you've never done it, you can never know it.
但情感如同呼吸一樣重要
But it's as vital as breath.
沒有感覺、沒有了愛
And without it... without love,
沒有憤怒、沒有悲傷...
without anger, without sorrow...
呼吸只不過是擺動的時鐘
breath is just a clock ticking.
那我只好將你還押
Then I have no choice but to remand you
給法院去執行了
to the Palace of Justice for processing.
執行
Processing.
你是指執刑是吧?
You mean execution, don't you?
執行
Processing.
槍炮武術
The Gun Katas.
經由上千次射擊紀錄分析
Through analysis of thousands of recorded gunfights,
教士已經決定
the Cleric has determined
在任何槍戰中,對手的幾何分佈位置
that the geometric distribution of antagonists in any gun battle
可經由統計預測得知
is a statistically predictable element.
槍炮武術與槍融合為一
MAN: The Gun Kata treats the gun as a total weapon,
每一個變化多端的招式皆展現出
each fluid position representing
最大的殺戮範圍,予以致命一擊
a maximum kill zone, inflicting maximum damage
打敗最大量的敵手
on the maximum number of opponents
在防守方面
while keeping the defender clear
可閃避回擊的傳統彈道
of the statistically traditional trajectories of return fire.
藉由此種招式的靈活運用
DUPONT: By the rote mastery of this art,
你的射擊威力至少將提升120%左右
your firing efficiency will rise by no less than 120%/。.
這致命性增加63%的差別
The difference of a 63%/。 increase to lethal proficiency
使得槍炮武術隊
makes the master of the Gun Katas
成為難以打敗的對手
an adversary not to be taken lightly.
[Thud]
沒有了愛...
O'BRIEN: [Echoing] Without love...
呼吸只不過是...擺動的時鐘
breath is just a clock... ticking.
[Flames roaring]
[Gasps]
[Breathing heavily]
[Heart beating]
[Thunder rumbles]
[Breathing heavily]
[Whirs]
波西安...解憂良藥
DUPONT: Prozium... the great nepenthe.
我們大眾的鎮靜劑
Opiate of our masses.
我們偉大社會的粘著劑
Glue of our great society.
救命良方
Salve and salvation,
解救我們脫離哀傷苦海
it has delivered us from pathos, from sorrow,
憂鬱和仇恨間的深邃壕溝
the deepest chasms of melancholy and hate.
有了它,我們才能麻醉悲傷
With it, we anesthetize grief,
摧毀嫉妒、消滅憤怒
annihilate jealousy, obliterate rage.
那些修女鼓吹的喜、愛與和樂
That those sister impulses towards joy, love, and elation
早已麻木了
are anesthetized in stride,
我們認為是種合理的犧牲
we accept as fair sacrifice.
因為我們可以完完全全地注射波西安
For we embrace Prozium in its unifying fullness
它的效果使得我們日益強大
and all that it has done to make us great.
[Loud footsteps]
早安,教士
Good morning, Cleric.
早安
Good morning.
...基本上,人類乃地球上的生物
...intrinsically, humans, as creatures of the Earth
到頭來總是回歸到一件事...戰爭
were drawn inherently always back to one thing... war.
因此我們不能只治標
And thus we seek to correct not the symptom
而是要治本
but the disease itself.
我們得將個人拋諸度外
We have sought to shrug off individuality,
取而代之為服從
replacing it with conformity.
取而代之...
Replacing it...
為平等...
with sameness...
為統一
with unity,
使得每個男人、女人、小孩
allowing each man, woman, and child
加入這個大家庭中
in this great society
過著完全相同的生活
to lead identical lives.
此同等環境架構的基本概念
The concept of identical environment construction
使得我們自信滿滿地迎接每一刻來臨
allows each of us to head confidently into each moment
儘管這種安全理念
with all the secure knowledge
很早以前就有了
it has been lived before.
[Voice fades]
你在做什麼?
What are you doing?
我在重新擺設我的桌子
I'm rearranging my desk.
你不喜歡之前的樣子嗎?
You didn't like the way it was before?
沒啥感覺
I had no feelings about it.
我只是想充分運用空間
I'm merely attempting to optimize.
感情罪犯窩藏在尼瑟斯裡
Sense offenders holed up in the Nether.
我們估計...我們估計有50人,長官
We estimate... we estimate 50 men, sir.
據收到情報,他們全部持有槍械
Intelligence tells us they're all fully armed.
就是這群人去炸波西安製藥廠的
This is the group that bombed the Prozium factories.
你們先沖,我們隨後掃蕩
You clean, we'll sweep.
遵命,長官
Yes, sir.
[Indistinct shouting]
沖! 沖! 沖! 沖!
Go! Go! Go! Go!
沖!
Go!
啊!
Aah!
攻下! 攻佔樓梯間!
Take it! Take the landings!
啊! 啊!
- Aah! - Aah!
-掩護我,我要進去 -啊...!
- Cover me. I'm going in. - Aaaaaaaah!
抓得好,教士
Nice grab, Cleric.
[Casings rattling]
[Door rattles, creaks]
[Door opens]
[Stairs creaking]
"貝多芬"
"Ludwig Van Beethoven."
[Record scratching]
[Powerful classical music plays]
[Music continues]
教士...
Cleric...
你為何不把那個留下
Why didn't you leave that
給證物組的人採集登記?
for the evidentiary team to collect and log?
他們偶爾會弄丟
They miss things sometimes.
我自己拿著...
I'll take it in myself...
比較保險
make sure it gets done properly.
[Sighs]
你知道,培斯頓...
You know, Preston...
如果我們繼續燒燬這些違禁品
If we keep burning all this contraband,
到最後就什麼也沒得燒了
eventually there won't be anything left to burn.
那像我們這種人還能幹什麼?
What'll there be for men like us?
長官!
Sir!
後方有發現
We got something out back.
[Men talking indistinctly]
我們還需要多派兩人來處理
We're gonna need two more men on this.
[Barking]
這些動物是女人小孩所飼養的
These animals were defended by women and children.
兩三下就解決掉了
We put them down easily.
又不是第一次碰到這種事了
This isn't the first time we've seen this.
他們幹嘛養這些動物?
Why do they keep these animals?
怎麼,難道他們...吃它們嗎?
What, do they... do they eat them?
你要我怎麼做,長官?
What do you want me to do, sir?
當然是全數消滅
Exterminate them, of course.
好了,動手吧
All right. Let's do it.
不
- No. - [Guns cocking]
怎麼了,教士?
What's wrong, Cleric?
沒事
Nothing.
[Barking continues]
[Gunshots, dogs whimpering]
嘿...
- Hey... - [Dog running]
抓住它
Grab it.
抓住它!
Grab it!
長官...把它丟回去
Sir... toss it back in.
我來解決掉它
I'll finish it off.
[Gun cocks]
把它交給我,長官
Give it to me, sir.
交給他,教士,他會解決它的
Give it to him, Cleric. He'll finish it.
[Whimpering]
[Whimpering continues]
等等!
Wait!
我覺得...
It seems to me that...
至少該留下一隻來做疾病測試
at least some of these animals ought to be tested for disease.
如果尼瑟斯裡有傳染病
If there's an epidemic in the Nether,
我們才好知道
it's best we know about it.
我不太懂你的邏輯,教士
I don't quite follow your logic, Cleric.
它們是反抗組織
They were Resistance.
它們本可帶我們深入地下社會
They could have led us to the Underground.
而非逮捕及審問
But instead of apprehension and interrogation,
將它們全數殺光
they were slaughtered.
是的,不過,教士,這種情形是...
Yes, but, Cleric, given the circumstances,
神父早已下令過
the Father has decreed
凡感情罪犯不再透過"訴訟程序"
that there will be no more "process" for sense offenders.
不是當場格殺
They are either to be shot on sight
就是不經審判直接火化
or incinerated without a trial.
但那樣與法律背道而馳
But it's counter to law.
你是議會一員,如果...
You're a member of the Council. If...
這不是議會的旨意
It is not the will of the Council,
是神父的旨意...他就是法律
it is the will of Father... and he is law.
長官...
Sir...
少了邏輯程序,豈不是成了濫殺無辜...
without the logic of process, is it not just mayhem...
那何必如此賣力去撲殺呢?
what we have worked so hard to eradicate?
你必須明白,培斯頓
You must understand, Preston,
不管你或是我同不同意
that while you... and even I... may not always agree with it,
都無關緊要
it is not the message that is important,
重要的是服從
it is our obedience to it.
神父的旨意
Father's will.
稱之為信仰
Call it faith.
我想你有吧?
You have it, I assume?
是的
Yes.
我有
I have it.
很好
Good.
[Click, whirring]
[Click]
收押證物X23-T45...
Confiscated evidence X23-T45...
瑪麗·歐布萊恩
Mary O'Brien.
[Exhales deeply]
[Car engine revs]
約翰·培斯頓教士進入尼瑟斯...
Cleric John Preston passing into the Nether...
執行任務
enforcement-related.
謝謝,長官
Thank you, sir.
[Whimpers]
我不知道還能拿你怎麼辦
I don't know what else to do with you.
去吧
Go on.
[Trunk door creaks]
[Trunk door closes]
快走!
Go!
[Keys jingle]
[Dog barks]
[Panting]
[Engine turns over]
[Yelps]
[Engine shuts off]
好吧
Fine.
不過你得待在後備箱裡
But you're going back in the trunk.
[Yelps]
[Chuckles]
好吧
Okay.
拿去
Here.
[Engines revving]
離開車子!
Step away from the vehicle!
最後一次警告!
This is your last warning!
離開車子!
Step away from the vehicle!
證件
Identification.
我是個教士
I'm a Cleric.
我來辦官方事務的
I'm here on official business.
證件!
Identification!
在我外套裡
It's in my coat.
外套在哪? 在哪?!
Where's the coat? Where is it?!
我沒帶
I don't have it.
有不明人士可能在進行破壞
Unidentified individuals are subject to summary destruction.
你犯了個極大的錯誤
You're making a very big mistake.
我是葛拉瑪頓教士,最高等級的
I'm a Grammaton Cleric, first class.
我們要搜查你的車子
We're gonna search your vehicle.
不,不用查,裡頭沒什麼
No, you're not. There's nothing in it.
快搜!
Search it!
-沒事,長官 -搜查後備箱
- Clear, sir. - Keys to the trunk.
我一直告訴過你
I'm trying to tell you.
我黎明前還得去見證火化
I have a predawn combustion to witness.
我不是...
I'm not...
隊長,這是在浪費我的時間
Captain, this is a waste of my time.
我叫約翰·培斯頓
My name is John Preston.
我是耶和華的最高等級教士...
I'm the highest-ranking Cleric of the Tetragramm...
等等
Wait.
站到一旁去
Stand off.
抱歉沒認出你來,長官
I'm sorry I didn't recognize you, sir.
沒關係,你們只是在執行勤務而已
That's okay. Just doing your job.
謝謝
Thank you.
我們會護送您回到門口
We'll escort you back to the gate.
謝謝
Thanks.
[Dog yelps]
動物
Animals.
尼瑟斯到處都是
Nether's full of them.
聲音好像是從你的後備箱裡傳來的
Sounds like it came from your trunk.
不可能
Impossible.
把鑰匙給我好了
Just give me my keys.
我會馬上離開
I'll be on my way.
隊長...
Captain...
我最後跟你再說一次...
I'm asking you one last time...
不要這麼做
don't do this.
跪下!
Down on your knees!
- 跪下! - 跪下!
- Down on your knees! - Down on your knees!
趴下!
Drop down!
趴到地上!快!
On the ground! Comply!
快點!
Do it!
不
No.
媽的!
Fuck!
什麼?
What?
啊,媽的!射他!射他!射他!
Aw, shit! Shoot him! Shoot him! Shoot him!
啊!
Aah!
[Casings rattling]
[Wind blowing]
[Exhales deeply]
[Grunting]
總是在練習, 教士
Always practicing, Cleric.
我想這就是為什麼你是最好的吧
I guess that's why you're the best.
可能我只是更好一點
Maybe I'm just better.
在想心事嗎?
Something on your mind?
[Both grunting]
為什麼這麼問?
Why do you ask?
直覺藝術, 教士
The intuitive arts, Cleric.
我的職責就是知你所想
It's my job to know what you're thinking.
[Mask thuds]
那...我現在在想什麼?
So, then... what am I thinking?
在想昨晚尼瑟斯的謀殺案...
About the murders in the Nether last night...
[Whooshing]
他們是否知道是誰做的
And if they know who did it.
[Both grunting]
我說的接近了嗎?
Am I close?
那麼,告訴我...他們知道嗎?
So, tell me... do they know?
[Panting]
有一些猜測
There are theories.
我自己也有幾種但是就目前來看...
I have one or two of my own, but at the moment...
都不成熟!
[Straining] They're premature!
我很高興發生了這件事
I'm glad it happened.
為什麼?
Why?
因為現在神父和教會
Because now Father and the Council
頒布了加速鎮壓情感犯的法令
have decreed an acceleration in the crackdown on offenders.
不管是誰做的...
Whoever did it...
都是加速了叛軍的滅亡
all they accomplished was a quicker end to the Resistance.
將會有場大屠殺的, 教士
It's gonna be a massacre, Cleric.
我是來告訴你...在尼瑟斯有一場大搜捕...
I came to tell you... there's a raid in the Nether...
7區
Sector 7.
[Panting]
準備一下吧
So get ready.
從後面的門走...
That door behind you...
走啊
Go.
走啊,他媽的!
Go, damn you!
離開這兒,天殺的! 如果你們不走就死定了!
Get out of here, God damn it! If you don't, you're dead!
別聽他的. 他會從後面槍殺我們的
Don't do it. He'll shoot us in the back.
如果我要槍殺你們, 我會面對面的做的
If I was gonna shoot you, I'd shoot you in the face.
快走.
Now go.
他媽的!跟我來
Damn you! Follow me.
快!快走!
Now! Let's go!
以後將不再拘留人犯
MAN: There will be no detention.
再說一遍... 將不再用任何方式拘留人犯
Repeat... no detention for any purpose.
所有人犯都將被處決.
All prisoners and apprehendees are to be put down.
小心!
Look out!
啊!
Aah!
Aaaah!
教士,出什麼事了? 我們聽到了槍聲
Cleric, what's happening? We heard gunshots.
走!
Go!
你在幹什麼? 教士!
What are you doing? Cleric!
他們是叛軍
They're Resistance fighters.
教士!
Cleric!
他是個情感罪犯!
He's a sense offender!
[Indistinct shouting]
守住所有出口!
Cover all quadrants!
四處搜查!
Secure the perimeter!
怎麼回事?
What is this?
你們在幹什麼?!
What are you doing?!
做得好,教士
Nicely done, Cleric.
你把他們趕進了陷阱...
You drive them into the trap...
我來收口
I close it.
真是典型的...團隊合作
The very definition of... teamwork.
你不覺得麼?
Don't you think?
你為什麼不享受一下親手處決 他們的榮譽呢,教士?
Why don't you take the honors of the execution, Cleric?
這些人應該被送去臨床審查
These people should be taken for clinical interrogation.
教士...
Cleric...
神父的指示非常明確
Father's rulings are quite clear.
罪犯們應被當場槍決
Offenders are to be shot on sight.
他們有很有價值的情報
They have valuable information.
教士...
Cleric...
留著他們還有更大的用處
They can be put to much better use.
教士
Cleric.
如果你的彈藥不夠, 請用我的
If your weapon's low, please, use mine.
[Gun cocks]
不
No.
我覺得,還是...
I think, in the end...
你自己來比較好
it'll be better if you have it.
隊長
Captain.
是,長官.準備射擊
Yes, sir. Firing positions.
預備...
CAPTAIN: Ready...
[Guns cocking]
瞄準...
Aim...
射擊!
Fire!
[Gunfire]
[Men screaming]
長官?
PRESTON: Sir?
什麼事, 教士?
Yes, Cleric?
你叫我做神父的
You asked me to become Father's instrument
鎮壓叛亂的工具
against the Resistance.
我準備好了
I'm ready.
今天
Today.
我想表現一下我的忠誠
I wish to show my faith.
我想,在您的許可下
I wish, with your permission,
去徹底查出地下組織的根據地
to locate the Underground once and for all.
以便摧毀它
To destroy it.
好,你去做吧
Good. Do it.
我非常...
I'm so...
非常抱歉
so very sorry.
這是他死時帶在身上的東西
These are the possessions he had on him at the time of death.
非法的東西將跟他一起被焚化
The illegal ones will be burned with him.
好
Good.
艾洛·帕崔吉
Errol Partridge.
這個名字對我應該有意義嗎?
The name supposed to mean something to me?
他曾是秩序、教士, 一流的,你認識他
He was a Grammaton Cleric, first class. You knew him.
新聞公告 ... 我是個情感罪犯
News bulletin... I'm a sense offender.
我不跟教士們在一起的
I don't hang around much with the Cleric.
我想知道他的事
I want to know about him.
好吧...
Well...
我建議你自己去問他
I suggest you go ask him.
但我知道他已經死了...
But I understand that he's dead...
被你在耶和華的朋友殺死的
killed by your friends at the Tetragrammaton.
不是被我的朋友殺死的
Not by my friends.
是被我
By me.
啊!
Aaah!
你們曾是戀人
You were lovers.
[Door closes]
地下組織是我們的反對者
The Underground is our foe,
比那些拒用情感控制劑的人
and greater than even the threat
對我們的威脅大得多的是
of those who have forsaken their Prozium for emotion
一群聯合在一起的情感犯
is the threat of those selfsame individuals united.
他們是個秘密組織...
They are the secret organization...
所以,神父下了手諭
And thus, it is in the writing of the Father
要我們找出我們最大的...
that we find our greatest...
下午好,長官
Good afternoon, sir.
您來是想要什麼?
What will it be for you?
最新的控制劑?
The latest copy of the inserts?
更新的宣言?
Revised edition of the manifesto?
艾洛·帕崔吉
Errol Partridge.
你知道些他的什麼情況?
What do you know about him?
您說什麼?
I beg your pardon?
都出去,快點
Everyone out. Now.
我再問你一次
I'm gonna ask you one more time.
艾洛·帕崔吉... 你知道他些什麼情況?
Errol Partridge... what do you know about him?
您肯定是弄錯了...
I'm sure this must be some mis...
- 你是個情感犯 - 我不是
- You're an offender. - I'm not.
不是? 那你為什麼這麼怕我?
No? Then why are you so scared of me?
現在,你得告訴我你所知道的 艾洛·帕崔吉的所有情況
Now, you will tell me everything you know about Errol Partridge,
不然我就把你抓起來
or I will have a wagon come to take you
送去毀滅堂燒掉
to the Hall of Destruction for summary combustion.
我...真的不知道...
[Breathing heavily] L-I really don't know...
說!
Speak!
他...他曾經跟一個叫吉根的人一起來過
He... he'd come in here with a fellow named Jurgen.
為什麼來?
Why?
我...我就知道這麼多,我發誓
That's... that's all I know. I swear.
吉根!
Jurgen!
有意思
Interesting.
- 呃-哦! - 呃!
- Ugh-ow! - Ugh!
[Groans]
[Gun cocks]
我們監視你很久了, 培斯頓
We've been watching you, Preston.
你是吉根
You're Jurgen.
你有情感
You're feeling.
知道你為什麼要來嗎?
Do you know why you came?
[Buzzes]
歡迎來到地下
Welcome to the Underground.
波動器
Polygraph.
它能探測人情感的波動
It detects fluctuations of human emotion.
我們必須要肯定
We have to be sure.
瑪麗
Mary.
你左口袋裡有
You're carrying in your left pocket
帶著她的體香的紅絲帶
a red ribbon sprayed with her scent.
在你覺得沒有人會看到的地方
You breathe it in sometimes
你會時不時的聞聞它
when you think there's no one to see.
但是你的情感...
But what you feel...
你的情感只有
what you feel could only be satisfied
在你全心愛上她的時候 才能得到滿足
by falling yourself into her.
她已經被安排焚化了...
She's scheduled for combustion...
明天
tomorrow.
我知道
I know.
你知道,我很像你
You know, I was like you.
但是你需要瞭解的關於 情感的第一件事
But the first thing you learn about emotion
就是它有它的代價...
is that it has its price...
就像個潘多拉魔盒
a complete paradox.
但是沒有壓抑...
But without restraint...
沒有控制...
without control...
情感就是混亂
emotion is chaos.
但那有什麼區別...
But how is that diff...
不同的是當我們想擁有情感的時候
The difference being is that when we want to feel,
我們能擁有
we can.
只不過...
It's just that...
我們中有些人...
some of us...
我們中有些人不得不放棄這種奢侈
some of us have to forgo that luxury
才能讓其他的人享受到
so that the rest can have it.
我們中的極少數
Some very few of us
必須強迫自己不要有情感
have to force ourselves not to feel.
像我這樣
Like me.
像你那樣
Like you.
我能做什麼?
What can I do?
你能殺了神父
You can kill Father.
[Man speaking indistinctly]
[Horn honks]
[Engines roaring]
約翰·培斯頓教士...
- Cleric John Preston... - [Gun cocks]
馬上跟我們走一趟
You are to come with us immediately.
培斯頓教士
DUPONT: Cleric Preston.
長官
Sir.
我聽到了最讓我不安的謠傳
I've heard the most disturbing rumor.
謠傳,長官?
Rumor, sir?
是的
Yes.
謠傳說我們中有個人
A rumor maintaining that one of us,
教士中的某一個
one of the Cleric,
秘密停止使用情感控制劑
has secretly taken it upon himself to cease his dose,
我們的一個精英
that one of our elite number
事實上是有情感的
is actually feeling.
情感,長官?
Feeling, sir?
你是在耍我嗎, 教士?!
Are you playing with me, Cleric?!
[Guns cock]
不,長官
No, sir.
我聽說這個人
This person, I'm told,
正在試圖與叛軍聯繫
is actually attempting to contact the Resistance.
告訴我,如果你願意的話
Now tell me, if you'll be so kind,
你到底...
how exactly...
在你遲到的這段時間都做了些什麼
have you been making use of your time of late?
嘗試同叛軍聯繫,長官
Attempting to contact the Resistance, sir.
嘗試?
Attempting?
你怎麼能查出這個叛徒
How is it that you intend to expose this traitor
如果你只是在"嘗試"?
if all you do is attempt?
你是...
You're...
完完全全的...
absolutely...
百分之百的正確,長官
100%/。 right, sir.
那當然了
Of course I am.
教士們是最後的防線
The Cleric is the final line of defense.
如果叛軍瓦解了他們
If the Resistance compromises it,
我們就完了
we are doomed.
神父就完了
Father is doomed.
我會加倍努力的,長官
I will redouble my efforts, sir,
去尋找叛軍
to locate the Resistance,
去查出那個叛徒
to find this traitor,
帶他們來接受教會的審判
and bring them all to the Council's fair justice.
去做吧
Do it.
[Creaking]
你在幹什麼?
What are you doing?
我,呃...
I, uh...
我在檢查看你是不是...
I was checking to make sure you've been...
在使用控制劑
taking your interval.
那你滿意嗎?
And are you satisfied?
是的,很滿意
Yes, I am.
晚安,爸爸
Good night, Dad.
我不明白
MARY: I don't understand.
我的處決都已經定下來了
My execution's set.
你還來做什麼?
Why are you here?
[Distant buzzing]
[Beeping]
[Beeping stops]
[Buzzing stops]
你不要用藥嗎?
Aren't you gonna dose?
我的天啊
My God.
你...
What...
你想怎麼辦?
What'll you do?
我不知道
I don't know.
50個清道夫,可能更多
50 sweepers, maybe more.
那接見怎麼樣?你能安排一次接見嗎?
What about an audience? Can you arrange to meet with him?
神父在劇變後就從來沒有接見過任何人
Father's never given a single audience since the upheaval.
暗殺的危險太大了
The danger of assassination is too great.
你一生都被訓練應付這種事情
They trained you your whole life to fight these kind of odds.
即使我能...
Even if I could...
即使我能夠做到
even if I could make it through,
又有什麼保障
what guarantee is there it would accomplish anything,
能讓情況變得不一樣?
that anything would be different?
我們有張你想像不到的巨大網絡
We have a network that's larger than you could ever imagine.
只要一聽說神父已死
Instant word comes that Father is dead,
教會無首
that the Council is leaderless.
已經安裝好的炸彈就會被引爆
Bombs that have already been planted will be set off
全利比亞的控制所和控制劑生產廠都會被炸掉
at Prozium clinics and factories around Libria.
如果我們能成功中斷供給
If we can succeed in disrupting the supply
即使只有一天...一天...
for even one day... one day...
人的本性就會讓我們成功
our cause will be won by human nature itself.
那戰爭怎麼辦,那些現在已經不存在的 殘忍的一切?
What about war, the everyday cruelties that are all gone now?
不過是被換成了耶和華的暴政
Replaced by the touch of Grammaton.
你願意去做嗎?
Will you do it?
[Exhales slowly]
是的
Yes.
你能做到嗎?
Can you?
我不知道
I don't know.
不要...
Don't...
見她最後一面
Seeing her one last time
只會讓你更難於做你必須要做的事
will only make it harder to do what you have to do.
[Man speaking indistinctly]
...專門設計用於對付這個
...designed especially to deal with it.
教士是執行者
The Cleric was implemented
被派出搜尋和毀滅
and sent out to search and destroy
那些殘留的東西
such objects that remained
還有,如果有必要,那些試圖...
and, if necessary, those who attempted to...
查詢視頻檔案
File footage.
教會...
The Council...
維維安娜·培斯頓
Viviana Preston.
判決和焚化
Sentence and incineration.
聲音
Auditory.
維維安娜·培斯頓
Viviana Preston,
因你中止使用控制劑, 因情感罪
for ceasing your interval, for the crime of feeling,
你被宣告有罪
you stand condemned
將承受被焚化的痛苦
to suffer annihilation in the city furnaces.
你將立刻被帶去焚化
You will be taken there immediately, and you will burn.
[Man speaking indistinctly]
教士是執行者
The Cleric was implemented
被派出搜尋和毀滅
and sent out to search and destroy
那些殘留的東西
such objects that remained
還有,如果有必要,那些試圖...
and, if necessary, those who attempted to...
教會...
The Council...
[Rapid footsteps approaching]
焚化...完成了嗎?!
The incineration... has it gone through?!
現在正在進行
It's going through now.
嗨!
Hey!
[Fire roaring]
[Quivering]
機器渦輪啟動
WOMAN: Machine turbines priming.
Machine turbines priming.
耶和華... 我要跟這個女人說幾名!
Tetragrammaton... I need to speak to this woman!
太遲了,長官.時間鎖已經開啟了
You're too late, sir. The time lock is engaged.
如果我們現在強制打開門
If we force the door now,
渦輪會爆炸的
the turbines will explode at street level.
...人員,立即撤出本區域
...personnel, clear the area immediately.
所有未經授權的人員, 立即撤出本區域
All unauthorized personnel, clear the area immediately.
渦輪已啟動
Turbines primed.
10秒鐘後點火...
Fire in 10 seconds...
9秒...
9 seconds...
8秒...
8 seconds...
7 秒...
7 seconds...
6 秒...
6 seconds...
5 秒...
5 seconds...
4 秒...
4 seconds...
3 秒...
3 seconds...
2 秒...
2 seconds...
渦輪...點火
Turbines... fire.
約翰·培斯頓教士...
Cleric John Preston...
你被捕了
You are under arrest.
這個人...
This man...
這個高級教士...
this senior Cleric...
停用了控制劑
has ceased the dose.
他現在有情感!
He is feeling!
他就是那個蛀蟲
He is the worm that has been eating at the core
腐蝕我們核心的蛀蟲!
of our great society!
我...
And I...
我把他帶來接受你們的審判
I have brought him for your justice.
呃!
Ugh!
我告訴過你我會靠你成就我的事業的,培斯頓
I told you I'd make my career with you, Preston.
副主席...
Vice-Council...
這個人犯了
This man is guilty
與情感犯交往罪
of consorting with sense offenders,
與女性交往罪
of having relations with a female,
還有情感罪本身
of sense crime itself.
派一個搜索隊去教士的住處
Dispatch a search team to the Cleric's quarters
去搜尋未使用的...
to search for unused...
嗯,沒有那個必要,長官.
Uh, that won't be necessary, sir.
如果您追蹤一下他的武器使用記錄
If you'll run the trace record on his side arm,
您會發現他就是
you will find that it was he
謀殺那支清掃隊的人
who was with the sweeper team when they were murdered.
教士...
Cleric...
我覺得你應該有事跟我說
I assume you have something to say to me.
我知道...
I know...
這很難相信...
it's hard to believe...
[Spits]
...一個耶和華的教士
...that a Cleric of the Tetragrammaton
會背叛自己受教導的一切
could turn his back on everything he's been taught,
成為叛軍的一員
would become associated with the Resistance,
甚至成為地下組織的戰士
even becoming a champion in its Underground.
但這是真的
But it's true.
我保證我會把那個人給您帶來
I promised that I would bring you that man.
我做到了
And I have.
- 勃蘭特教士... - 長官?
- Cleric Brandt... - Sir?
追蹤顯示是你的槍
The trace shows that it was your gun
出現在尼瑟斯的清道夫旁邊
in the Nether with the sweepers.
不可能
That's impossible.
[Guns cock]
你們搞錯了
This is wrong.
我覺得,還是....
PRESTON: I think, in the end...
還是你來比較好
it'll be better if you have it.
他掉包了
He switched them.
看啊,他的槍在我手上
See, I have his gun now.
當然了,你逮捕我的時候從我身上拿走的
Of course you do. You took it when you arrested me.
什麼?
What?
帶他去毀滅堂
Take him to the Hall of Destruction
進行審判和焚化
for summary judgment and combustion.
等一下,等一下,聽我解釋啊
Wait, wait, wait. Wait! I can explain this.
呃,長官,我沒有情感!
Uh, sir, I'm not feeling!
他才是有情感的!
He is the one who's feeling!
你們搞錯了!
This is a mistake!
當然...
Of course...
既然有人提出申訴
since a complaint has been lodged,
根據法典我會派一組人
law and the letter is that I allow a team
去搜查你們的住處
to carry out the search of your premises.
你覺得那有必要嗎, 教士?
Do you think that's entirely necessary, Cleric,
或者是我太...謹慎了?
or am I being too... exacting?
我聽您的,長官
As you say, sir,
根據法典來吧
it's the law and the letter.
你的一個同事走到了盡頭
And it doesn't disturb you in the least
你一點都不覺得不安嗎?
that your colleague is going to his end?
我唯一覺得不安的事是,長官
The only thing that disturbs me, sir,
我雖然身為神父對付地下組織的一個工具
is that I am Father's instrument against the Underground,
但是...我至今未有機會面見他老人家
and yet... I've never had the honor of meeting him.
呣...
Hmm.
是的.但是,教士,你知道
Yes, but, Cleric, you know
神父從來不接見任何人
that Father never grants an audience to anyone.
即使是給他查出叛軍的人?
Even to the man who brings him the Resistance?
[Tires screech]
對不起,長官,例行檢查
Sorry, sir. Just a formality.
搜索隊馬上就到
The search team will be up momentarily.
很好,我沒什麼好隱藏的
Excellent. I have nothing to hide.
搜索隊已經在裡面了,長官
The search teams are already inside, sir.
很好
- [Beeps] - Excellent.
[Men speaking indistinctly in distance]
在找東西嗎?
ROBBIE: Looking for something?
如果我是你...
If I were you...
我以後會更小心一點
I'd be more careful in the future.
多長時間了?
How long?
從媽媽死後就開始了
Since Mom.
麗莎呢?
And Lisa?
當然了
Of course.
你怎麼知道的?
How did you know?
你忘記了...
You forget...
我的工作就是知道你的思想
it's my job to know what you're thinking.
那你知道我現在要做什麼了
Then you know what I'm gonna do now.
你有話要跟副主席說嗎?
You have a message for the Vice-Council?
任務完成了
It's done.
我找到叛軍基地
I've located the Resistance.
馬上過來
Come now.
就能全殲他們
You'll have them all.
在神父跟你說話之前不要先跟他說話
Do not address Father unless first addressed by him.
不要直視他
Avoid eye contact.
如果你闖進了他的個人安全區
If you should break his personal security zone,
你將馬上被狙擊手槍殺
you will be immediately put down by snipers.
明白了嗎?
Is that understood?
當然,你要交出你的武器
You'll be required to surrender your firearm, of course,
然後還要進行一次測試
and then there's the test.
測試?
Test?
是的
Yes.
不能想像我們能讓神父
You didn't imagine we would risk exposing Father
與一個即使像你這樣忠實的下屬接觸
to even such a dedicated servant as yourself
而不對你進行測試, 對不對?
without first having tested you, did you?
請
Please.
[Mechanical whirring]
[Man speaking indistinctly]
教士...
Cleric...
請交出你的武器
your weapon, please.
這邊
Here.
請坐
Sit.
我們先從一個測試問題開始
We'll start with a test question first.
事實上更像是個謎語
[Snaps fingers] More of a riddle, actually.
你要說的是用什麼方法最簡單
What would you say is the easiest way
能從一個耶和華教士手裡取到武器?
to get a weapon away from a Grammaton Cleric?
[Guns cocking]
你找他要
You ask him for it.
我告訴我你我會靠你成就我的事業的,教士
I told you I'd make my career with you, Cleric.
...去組織力量...
...to combine the capacity...
培斯頓...
Preston...
勃蘭特的任務很簡單...
Brandt's job was simple...
讓你覺得自己贏了
to make you feel like you'd won,
讓你覺得安全
to make you feel safe.
許多年來,我試圖安插一個內線
For years, I tried to infiltrate an agent
到地下組織裡...
into the Underground...
...直到我發現了你...
...until it hit me...
為了進入他們中間而不被發現
in order to pass undetected into their midst,
為了取得他們的信任
in order to be trusted by them,
我的內線必須要想他們所想
my provocateur would have to think like them
並且必須要感受他們所感
and would have to feel like them.
但是到哪兒去找這樣一個人...
But where to find such a man...
一個有能力感覺他從未感覺到的情感?
a man with the capacity to feel who didn't yet know it?
但是...
But...
我們從來沒見過面
we've never met.
沒有?
No?
別這麼驚訝, 培斯頓
Don't look so surprised, Preston.
為什麼神父要比
Why should Father be more real
其他的政治木偶更真實?
than any other political puppet?
真正的神父幾年前就死了
The real Father died years ago.
教會只是選舉我
The Council simply elected me
來繼承他的事業
to pursue his paternal tradition.
還有你, 培斯頓
And you, Preston,
叛軍想像中的救世主
the supposed savior of the Resistance,
現在成了他們的毀滅者
are now its destroyer,
還有,跟他們一起,你自己也露出了原形...
and, along with them, you've given me yourself...
冷靜的...
calmly...
沉著的...
cooly...
完全不出意外的
entirely without incident.
[Polygraph machine scribbling rapidly]
不
No.
[Beeping]
哦...
Oh...
媽的
Shit.
不是不出意外
Not without incident.
我來了
I'm coming.
你真該學會敲門的
You really should learn to knock.
感覺怎麼樣, 培斯頓?
How did it feel, Preston?
[Growls softly]
- 啊! - 呃! 呃! 呃-啊!
- Agh! - Ugh! Ugh! Uhh-ah!
哇!
Wah!
呃! 啊! 呃!
Ugh! Agh! Uhh!
呃!
Ugh!
- 啊! - 啊!
- Aggh! - Aggh!
注意我的制服, 教士
Mind the uniform, Cleric.
[Whooshing]
我準備穿很長時間的
I plan to be wearing it for a long time.
[Thud]
小心點, 培斯頓
Be careful, Preston.
"你踩在我的夢想之翼上"
You're treading on my dreams.
哦!
Ohh!
等一下!
Wait!
Wait.
看著我
Look at me.
[Breathing heavily]
我是活生生的
I'm life.
我活著,我呼吸...
I live, l-I breathe...
[Breathes deeply]
我有感覺
I feel.
現在你知道了...
Now that you know it...
你真的能下得了手嗎?
can you really take it?
這真的值得嗎?
Is it really worth the price?
我很樂意承受
I pay it gladly.
[Thud]
以下內容被定級為EC-10 ...
The following items have been rated EC-10...
有罪的
condemned.
[Speaking indistinctly]
[Thud]
在19世紀...
In the 19th century...
[All shouting indistinctly]
...世界臣服在它的腳下
...world to its knees.
二千年以前...
Two millennia ago...
在征服已知世界的過程中
in his conquest of the known world,
亞歷山大大帝屠殺了
Alexander the Great slaughtered
超過100萬人
more than one million human beings.
3個世紀後,只是出於嫉妒
Three centuries later, purely out of jealousy,
蓋斯·凱撒, "卡利古拉" 謀殺了他的親妹妹
Gaius Germanicus, "Caligula," murdered his own sister,
懷著他的親生骨肉
impregnated with his own child.
在...
In the...
[Electricity crackles]
[Speaking indistinctly, echoing]
以下內容被定級為EC-10 ...
...items have been rated EC-10...
...定級為有罪的,毀滅的
...rated condemned, destroyed.
[Sputtering]
...內容被定級為...
...items have been rated...
[Silence]
[Rumbling]
[Rumbling continues]
[Indistinct shouting, gunfire]
[Shouting continues]
[Men cheering]
[Slow instrumental music plays]
[Indistinct singing]
[Tempo quickens]
[Tempo slows]
[Mid-tempo music plays]
[Techno music plays]
[Tempo slows]
[Music ends]